Let's investigate this sequence we were
just looking at a little bit more
carefully because I want to give a
different view on what a sequence really
is. Now, currently I have it written
here horizontally, but I could also go
and switch it around and write it
vertically as well. That shouldn't make
any difference. It's still an infinite
ordered list. And I also have another
one that we've seen before. This is the
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 and so on. So, we can
think of these as two different
sequences.
But because I sort of line them up in
this nice way, we we should have this
association that like the one over here
is associated to the three in the sense
that they're both the first terms and
the two here and the minus 6 are
associated in the sense that they're
both the second terms. And I can think
of this as a sort of a dynamic way. I
can think of it as the one goes to the
three and the two goes to the minus 6
and the three goes to the 9. Indeed, the
association between here is precisely
what that explicit formula tells me. If
I choose a different K, it goes to the
-1 to the K * 3K.
So, what do I really have here? Well, if
I think about my sequences as being an
arrow diagram where I've got a domain
here and I've got a co-domain and then
the elements inside of my domain are all
mapped to things in my co-domain, what
I'm describing is a function. Every
single thing in my domain goes somewhere
and more importantly, it obeys the
vertical line test. there's there's no
element in my domain here that that
splits into multiple different things
because my association is to take one
element say the kith one to the kith one
over here not to two different ones. So
really what a sequence is going to be
then is this function from this
particular set to some other set or in
other words I'm going to say this is my
formal mathematically precise definition
a sequence is a function where I'm
taking things from the positive integers
that was the 1 2 3 4 and I'm going to
some co-domain that we haven't specified
in in the other example it looked like
it was integers as well but it's going
to be some co-domain Okay. So as an
example, let's take the one we just
looked at. If I want to describe it in
this language, the language is of a
function with a domain and with a
co-domain. What I'm going to say is that
I have a function f and it inputs things
inside of my co-domain. So it's going to
input some k.
And then I had to tell you what it does
to the k. Well, it does precisely what
we just saw. It's got that min -1 to the
k * 3k. This could be an example.
In other words, if I think of it as a
function, it it inputs the k and it
spits out this a subk.
Now, this formal definition of a
function, I I want us to note it and to
be there and for us to to think that
sequences really aren't anything new.
They're just a special type of function.
However, it's really intuitively useful
to us if we if we actually think of
sequences more in the informal sense
that they're this ordered list of
numbers. In other words, I typically
don't use the f of k notation at all.
When I'm denoting a sequence, I will say
a subk, the kth term in my sequence, and
I will give the formula that depends on
k. And I don't make explicit that I'm
talking about a function, and I will
make explicit a particular f. However,
that is what is going on behind the idea
of a sequence.